familyvideo.com 2019-05-31

# Privacy Policy | Family Video

This privacy policy explains Family Video’s practices regarding how it collects, uses, protects or otherwise handles your personal information collected on FamilyVideo.com website and mobile programs.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our email list, fill out a form, or enter information on our site. 

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our email list or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize the user experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
  * To quickly process your transactions.
  * To ask for ratings and reviews of services or products
  * To follow up with customers after correspondence (live chat, email or phone inquiries)

**How do we protect visitor information?**

Family Video implements a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

**Do we use 'cookies'?**

We collect and/or place both an IP Address and Cookies. This information is kept for the sole purpose of remembering you each time you return to our online store. It protects both you as the shopper and us as the store when identifying you and authenticating your purchases. This information will only be used in the case of site misuse. 

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. 

If you disable cookies, some features will be disabled that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. However, you can still place orders.

In order to protect yourself against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer, be sure to log out when using a shared computer. 

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety. 

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions as they relate to our website.

**CAN-SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Provide you updates regarding your order
  * Send informational messages
  * Provide you with special offers
  * Request your feedback in order to improve your experience with us

By ordering items from Family Video, you consent to receive communications from us electronically. Electronic communications will satisfy any legal requirement as written notification; including notices, agreements, disclosures and the like.

**To be in accordance with CAN-SPAM, Family Video agrees to the following:**

**If at any time you would like to subscribe/unsubscribe from any of our emails** , you can go to My Account to manage your subscriptions. You may also contact us at [**orders@familyvideo.com**](mailto:orders@familyvideo.com) and we'll promptly update your preferences.

**Video Privacy Protection Act of 1988**  
Family Video supports the Video Privacy Protection Act of 1988 and will use reasonable effort to require employee and business partner compliance with the Act.

**Children Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.  
We do not specifically market to children under 13. While Family Video does sell children's products, only adults over the age of 18 may purchase products from FamilyVideo.com.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy.

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**   
Users can visit our site anonymously. 

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy' and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes: 

  * On our Privacy Policy Page

Users are able to change their personal information: 

  * By emailing us  

  * By calling us

**Fair Information Practices**  
The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

  * We will notify the users via email within 7 business days
  * We will notify the users via in-site notification within 1 business day

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

Family Video will update this Privacy Policy from time to time in response to changing legal, regulatory or operational requirements. Notice of any such changes will be given in accordance with law. Changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy. Family Video will not use your personal information in a manner materially different than what was stated at the time it was collected without your consent.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, please contact us by email at [**orders@familyvideo.com**](mailto:orders@familyvideo.com).  
Alternatively, you can write to us at the following address: Family Video, 2500 Lehigh Avenue, Glenview, IL 60026 U.S.A. 

**Last updated:** April 26, 2016
